In this tutorial, we will introduce you to the new feature in the 2024 version, the automatic virtual model.
You can automatically convert the virtual model created in other software to the default virtual model of Marvelous Designer.
Click the main menu, virtual model, automatically convert virtual model.
In the automatic virtual model window, you can import your virtual model here in the original file.
You can import AVT, OBJ or FBX files. We recommend that you use APOS virtual model.
According to gender, age, choose the right default virtual model type.
You can choose the default female, male, female, boy, boy or baby virtual model of Marvelous Designer.
In the option to convert, you can choose to automatically or automatically convert.
As for default, you can choose default.
Choose default when you can để September
The default virtual model's posture and size can be adjusted, so that the resubmit result is accurate.
You can head to the main menu, virtual model, virtual model editor, and change size.
Click ShiftX, open the connections to change the posture, and try to get the default model near the prototype.
When you choose to remove the hand and foot, the model's hand and foot will be converted into the hand and foot of the default virtual model of Marvelous Designer.
What is the introduction of the conversion type?
When choosing the MD skin type, the body type of the prototype will be kept, only the outer shape will be converted, and the model type of the model will be changed.
to the appearance of the Marvelous Designer virtual model and increase the joint points.
When choosing the only binding bone structure, it will maintain the original model's body shape and appearance, please increase the joint points.
When choosing the size to be edited, it will use the body shape of the current virtual model and increase the joint points,
so that you can use the virtual model editor to modify its size in Marvelous Designer.
In the save path, you can set the saved file name and file path.
Click the convert button to start converting virtual models according to your image.
After the conversion is complete, choose to open the file folder and open the file folder where the converted virtual model is located.
Click close and go to the 3D window to see these converted virtual models.
These three virtual models are in the order of MD skin type, binding bone structure, size, and edit to the left and right in the 3D window.
Now let's import an FBX file that does not have a binding bone structure and select the MD skin type and only bind the bone structure for automatic conversion.
Now you can see that by automatically converting virtual models, even if the original model does not have a binding bone structure, it can automatically bind the bone structure.
In addition, in the new version, support at the same time preserves the arrangement of multiple virtual models and the arrangement version.
Virtual models that have been converted can now use the functions that only Marvelous Designer virtual models can use, such as using random action files, opening up software model simulation, and more follow-up functions.